<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="wordpress/2.0" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">

<channel>
	<title>BIT-101 Blog</title>
	<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog</link>
	<description>Really pulls the room together.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2006 17:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0</generator>
	<language>en</language>
			<item>
		<title>Mini Laser Projector on its way</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=735</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=735#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 21:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If anyone was at FlashForward San Francisco 2004, and you saw Bill Buxton&#8217;s opening talk, you&#8217;ll certainly remember the little device he showed off. It was a laser projector about the size of a pack of cigarettes, that could project an image on any surface. He used it to project some photos. It was one [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If anyone was at FlashForward San Francisco 2004, and you saw Bill Buxton&#8217;s opening talk, you&#8217;ll certainly remember the little device he showed off. It was a laser projector about the size of a pack of cigarettes, that could project an image on any surface. He used it to project some photos. It was one of the coolest things I&#8217;ve seen. He predicted that we would start seeing them on the market in a year or two.</p>
<p>Well, it&#8217;s been two years, and I finally saw the first mention of one of these devices on Engadget. Here it is:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.engadget.com/media/2006/02/pvpro.jpg" /><br />
And here&#8217;s a link:</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.engadget.com/2006/02/13/new-pvpro-mini-projector-has-no-moving-parts/">http://www.engadget.com/2006/02/13/new-pvpro-mini-projector-has-no-moving-parts/</a></p>
<p>A few details I remember from his talk will point up how cool these devices will eventually be.</p>
<p>1. Because it uses lasers (the same lasers in the supermarket barcode scanners), there is no need for focusing. The beams just scan across and create the image on any surface, literally laser sharp.</p>
<p>2. The demo he showed and the model shown in the link above are monochrome. At the time he said it was because blue lasers were hard to produce and expensive, but some breakthrough had just occurred to make them easier and cheaper, so we should soon see RGB output.</p>
<p>3. Think about that supermarket scanner. It doesn&#8217;t just project an image, it can read the surface it&#8217;s reflecting off of. Same with these projectors eventually. It will be able to detect, for example, when you move your hand on the image. Get this concept: You walk into a restaurant, hook this up to your pda, shine it on an empty surface of the table and start showing your presentation to your client. You reach down with your finger and start moving things around, clicking buttons. Yes, the restaurant table is now an interactive touch screen!</p>
<p>It looks like we&#8217;re still a ways off from seeing consumer versions of these things, but it is exciting to see this device at least mentioned. It is still one of the things that I am really looking forward to in the future.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=735</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>flickr as a news source</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=734</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=734#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 02:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=734</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Earlier I was reading a blog post by Alexander McCabe on how people are starting to determine someone&#8217;s credentials by how many google hits their name gets:
http://www.centralquestion.com/archives/2006/02/a_google_nobody.html
It&#8217;s interesting how technology is changing the way we do things, find out about things, etc. I just realized today that flickr can be a great local news source. [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier I was reading a blog post by Alexander McCabe on how people are starting to determine someone&#8217;s credentials by how many google hits their name gets:</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.centralquestion.com/archives/2006/02/a_google_nobody.html">http://www.centralquestion.com/archives/2006/02/a_google_nobody.html</a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s interesting how technology is changing the way we do things, find out about things, etc. I just realized today that flickr can be a great local news source. Well, at least for pictures of local news.<br />
Today I was down by the local mall just after an SUV had driven through the local bookstore show window, into the cafe there. I go there all the time so it was pretty shocking to see a vehicle sticking halfway out of the store. I didn&#8217;t have my camera on me, so when I got home and told my wife about it, I tried going on line to see if any news sources had covered it. Nothing. The <a target="_blank" href="http://www.portersquarebooks.com/NASApp/store/IndexJsp">store itself</a> had a mention of it, but nothing else anywhere that I could find.</p>
<p>Then I realized that there were dozens of onlookers snapping away with their cell phone cameras. So what are they going to do with those pictures when they get home? flickr them, of course!</p>
<p>Went onto flickr, searched for &#8220;Porter Square&#8221;, sort by most recent, and instantly had a dozen photos, along with commentary by people who were there.</p>
<p>If you want to see the pics:</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/koranteng/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/koranteng/ </a></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/viewsnortheast/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/viewsnortheast/</a></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pingswept/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/pingswept/</a></p>
<p>(Nobody was killed, 3 people hurt, hopefully not too bad.)
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=734</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flex 2 and AS3 without Eclipse</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=733</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=733#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 16:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=733</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I wanted to call attention to a post by Sam Robbins regarding setting up a third party editor to compile Flex 2 and Eclipse. Of course, Flex Builder 2 is in public beta and is now free, but the free ride is going to expire soon, when the real deal comes out. Then you are [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to call attention to a post by <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.pixelconsumption.com/index.php?p=31">Sam Robbins</a> regarding setting up a third party editor to compile Flex 2 and Eclipse. Of course, Flex Builder 2 is in public beta and is now free, but the free ride is going to expire soon, when the real deal comes out. Then you are going to need to shell out some serious cash to continue playing with it.</p>
<p>If you are a serious Flex developer, earning your living by creating Flex applications, you should go forth and purchase it. A carpenter should buy the best tools he can afford. Likewise, a developer should have never hold back on paying for the best tools to do his job.</p>
<p>However, if you are just a hobbyist, or do the occasional Flex or AS3 app for fun, that&#8217;s deep reach into the wallet. Especially if you&#8217;re already paying for the Flash IDE on top of it.</p>
<p>The good news is that Adobe has announced that they will give away the command line compiler and framework for free! But now you need a way to edit your code and compile it. This comes down to two issues: having an editor that &#8220;knows about&#8221; mxml and as3, and setting up some kind of automated build and launch process.</p>
<p>Sam&#8217;s post addresses the second part. We actually worked together on this for a couple of days, getting it to work in the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sapien.com/">PrimalScript</a> editor. However, what is outlined there can easily be adapted to work with <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bit-101.com/blog/wp-admin/www.flashdevelop.org/community/">FlashDevelop </a>or <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sephiroth.it/python/sepy.php">SEPY</a>, as long as there is some way to launch an external program, in this case, Ant.bat. The setup that Sam wrote about allows you to launch the compiler, add any command line parameters that you want, use a specific flex-config.xml file, etc. It then compiles the new swf, moves it to a bin directory and lauches it right in the PrimalScript editor (something I didn&#8217;t even know was possible until earlier this week, and is totally awesome). Of course, if you are using another editor, you can substitute the standalone player instead of PrimalScript as an editor, or even create an html wrapper for the swf and launch that in a browser. Think of it more as a base script that you can customize to your own needs.</p>
<p>The first part of the problem is a little tougher to tackle. Currently, there are no xml schemas or as3 intrinsic files available. This means no code hinting, completion, parameter lists, etc. in any editor outside of Flex Builder 2. I&#8217;m not sure if Adobe will be releasing such things, but my feeling is that they won&#8217;t. Thus is will be up to the community to create them, and then up to the makers of editors to implement them. I can say this, that the next version of PrimalScript will almost certainly have AS3, and possibly Flex 2 support (as well as a lot of other mind blowing features, which I&#8217;d love to tell you about, but then I&#8217;d have to kill myself).</p>
<p>I can only assume that someone in the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.osflash.org/">OSFlash </a>community will start (or has already started) working on the project of creating intrinsic as3 files and a mxml schema. I&#8217;d be happy to join in the effort.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=733</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>XPath Query Tool version 1.1</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=732</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=732#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 17:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Added a field where you can load an external xml file. Just put in the url of the file or feed. If you download the swf and run it locally, you can also load files from your hard drive.
 http://www.bit-101.com/xpath/
Next I think I&#8217;ll attempt some proper formatting on the xml itself.

]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Added a field where you can load an external xml file. Just put in the url of the file or feed. If you download the swf and run it locally, you can also load files from your hard drive.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bit-101.com/xpath/"> http://www.bit-101.com/xpath/</a></p>
<p>Next I think I&#8217;ll attempt some proper formatting on the xml itself.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=732</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>More “Making Things Move” Reviews</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=731</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=731#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 15:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=731</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just ran across these two reviews of my book, Foundation ActionScript Animation: Making Things Move!
http://godbit.com/article/foundation-actionscript-animation
http://www.flashmagazine.com/1236.htm
I have to say, I had a feeling the book was going to be received well, but it has far surpassed my expectations. Thanks everyone for saying such nice things about it!

]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just ran across these two reviews of my book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/redirect?link_code=ur2&#038;tag=bit101-20&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=9325&#038;path=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Fproduct%2F1590595181%2Fqid%3D1138397807%2Fsr%3D2-1%2Fref%3Dpd_bbs_b_2_1%3Fs%3Dbooks%26v%3Dglance%26n">Foundation ActionScript Animation: Making Things Move!</a></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://godbit.com/article/foundation-actionscript-animation">http://godbit.com/article/foundation-actionscript-animation</a></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.flashmagazine.com/1236.htm">http://www.flashmagazine.com/1236.htm</a></p>
<p>I have to say, I had a feeling the book was going to be received well, but it has far surpassed my expectations. Thanks everyone for saying such nice things about it!
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=731</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Communist Links Exposed!!!</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=730</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=730#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 02:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=730</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was just writing up some stuff on the BitmapData class in MS Word. For the fillRect method, I drew a red square inside a bitmap. Mr. Clippy did not like this at all, and suggested the more formal &#8220;Red Square&#8221;.
Hey, I get my humor where I can. 

]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was just writing up some stuff on the BitmapData class in MS Word. For the fillRect method, I drew a red square inside a bitmap. Mr. Clippy did not like this at all, and suggested the more formal &#8220;Red Square&#8221;.</p>
<p>Hey, I get my humor where I can. <img src='http://www.bit-101.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=730</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Odd or Even in ActionScript</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=729</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=729#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2006 14:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=729</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just saw a great post over here: http://www.coldfusioncookbook.com/entry/53/How-do-I-determine-if-a-number-is-even-or-odd?
Actually, it was the first comment that was awesome. Were I to decide if a number is odd or even in ActionScript, I&#8217;d do the same thing the original post did (translated to AS):
iseven = ((num % 2) == 0)
The comment suggested a faster way using bitwise operators. [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just saw a great post over here: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.coldfusioncookbook.com/entry/53/How-do-I-determine-if-a-number-is-even-or-odd?">http://www.coldfusioncookbook.com/entry/53/How-do-I-determine-if-a-number-is-even-or-odd?</a></p>
<p>Actually, it was the first comment that was awesome. Were I to decide if a number is odd or even in ActionScript, I&#8217;d do the same thing the original post did (translated to AS):</p>
<p>iseven = ((num % 2) == 0)</p>
<p>The comment suggested a faster way using bitwise operators. Translated to AS it&#8217;s this:</p>
<p>iseven = ((num &#038; 1) == 0)</p>
<p>Makes sense when you look at binary numbers:</p>
<p>001 = 1</p>
<p>010 = 2</p>
<p>011 = 3</p>
<p>100 = 4</p>
<p>101 = 5</p>
<p>Each of the odd numbers has a 1 in the far right column. The even numbers have 0 there. Mask it with &#8220;&#038; 1&#8243; and you can see which it is.</p>
<p>A pretty minor difference syntactically, but bitwise operators are FAST. I&#8217;m not sure how mod (%) works internally, but I&#8217;d guess it does a fair amount of calculation.</p>
<p>Nice elegant solution.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=729</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Free XPath Query Tool</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=728</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=728#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 20:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=728</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was mucking about with some XML the last few days, and using XFactorStudio&#8217;s XPath to parse it. I was a little rusty on some of the syntax and I remembered a whlie back I was using Oxygen, which had a nice XPath visualizer in it. I got to thinking and realized that would be [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was mucking about with some XML the last few days, and using <a target="_blank" href="http://www.xfactorstudio.com/">XFactorStudio</a>&#8217;s XPath to parse it. I was a little rusty on some of the syntax and I remembered a whlie back I was using <a target="_blank" href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/">Oxygen</a>, which had a nice XPath visualizer in it. I got to thinking and realized that would be pretty easy to make in Flash. So here you have it, the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bit-101.com/xpath/">BIT-101 XPath Query Tool</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.bit-101.com/xpath/xpathtool.jpg" /></p>
<p>You can use it on line, or click the link to download the swf. It can be used standalone, or you could even drop it in your WindowSWF directory and have it be a panel inside Flash. Naturally, it requires installation of the XPath classes from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.xfactorstudio.com/">XFactorStudio</a>. <em>[Let me correct that. The swf itself does not require that you install the classes. But if you want to then go and build that query in your own file, you will need to install XPath.]</em></p>
<p>For the next version I&#8217;m going to try to make it so you can download an XML file from a URL, and maybe use SWF Studio to make a standalone EXE that you could load local XML files from.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=728</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>College Savings Planning Tool</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=727</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=727#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 22:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=727</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just discovered that a project I did for TIAA-Cref last year has gone live. It&#8217;s a college savings planning tool that they license to other companies. Looks like Georgia Higher Education Savings Plan is the first company to use it. Always nice to see your work go live.
Link: http://gacollegesavings529.com/
(Click on the button that says [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just discovered that a project I did for TIAA-Cref last year has gone live. It&#8217;s a college savings planning tool that they license to other companies. Looks like Georgia Higher Education Savings Plan is the first company to use it. Always nice to see your work go live.</p>
<p>Link: <a target="_blank" href="http://gacollegesavings529.com/">http://gacollegesavings529.com/</a></p>
<p>(Click on the button that says &#8220;Calculate your costs&#8221; on the lower right side.)
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=727</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Showing my Mac love.</title>
		<link>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=726</link>
		<comments>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=726#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 16:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kp</dc:creator>
		
	<category>General</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?p=726</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[www.bit-101.com

]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bit-101.com">www.bit-101.com</a>
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://www.bit-101.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=726</wfw:commentRSS>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>