<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="wordpress/1.5.1.2" -->
<rss version="0.92">
<channel>
	<title>FlashGuru Consulting</title>
	<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk</link>
	<description>Information for Flash Developers</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 15:32:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
	<language>en</language>

	<item>
		<title>Flash 8 Source Files - Free for all</title>
		<description>	IFBIN is now completely free to anybody and everybody, no subscription fees whatsoever. Which means that all my Flash 8 Source files are now free to download, amongst hundreds of other examples by some of the best developers in our community. Welcome to IFBIN 2.0 open source.

 </description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/flash-8-source-files-free-for-all/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Apollo Podcast</title>
		<description>	If your interested in the future of Flash as a platform, then Apollo is the next new part of the equation bringing the strengths of Flash to the desktop. 
	All of you should know of Mike Chambers, the community voice and face of Macromedia for along time and the man ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/apollo-podcast/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Adobe MAX still doesn’t pay speaker expenses!</title>
		<description>	Aral has the lowdown on why Adobe need to change their policy on covering expenses for presenters at MAX. Controversially in the past they have not paid for speakers flights and/or accomodation for the duration of the conference, similarly the speaker support is apparently “the worst” of all related industry ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/adobe-max-still-doesnt-pay-speaker-expenses/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Still waiting for Apollo?</title>
		<description>	An updated version of MDM Zinc V2.5 was released today, making the best projector tool able to support Flash 9 Movies and Flex 2 Applications. More info here, here and here.

 </description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/still-waiting-for-apollo-mdm-zinc-v25-now-supports-flex-2/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Square Circle website is live!</title>
		<description>	Its been  along time in the works and the guy’s over at Square Circle have finally got it live. I helped them out during the early stages with some coding for the spinning zoom concept, the quicknav and the interactive telephone in the contacts section. The site is looking ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/square-circle-website-is-live/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Im now a Mac dude</title>
		<description>	People who know me have often in the past heard me winge/moan &amp; denounce Mac users. Basically i have always been anti-mac because i dont know much/if anything about them (ignorance and lack of interest) but recently i decided i wanted to learn something new and add a bit of ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/im-now-a-mac-dude/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Flash Monster Trucks</title>
		<description>	Heres an addictive game for you to play during any downtime at work. Clever viral piece made by the gang over at Stimunation. Nice rigid body dynamics.

 </description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/flash-monster-trucks/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Flash 9 AS3 Preview</title>
		<description>	Windows users can now download a preview release of Flash 9 on Adobe Labs that is basically the same as Flash 8, but allows Flash Developers/Designers to output their content to Flash Player 9. 
	There is however one new awesome feature included in there for you to play with, the ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/flash-9-as3-preview/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>London Flash Platform User Group</title>
		<description>	A new user group has been formed in London to bring together like minded individuals interested in the Flash Platform. The first gathering will take place on the 22nd June at Play Bar on Old Street. Come along, get some drinks down, watch the presentations and talk about all things ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/london-flash-platform-user-group/</link>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Barcelona baby!</title>
		<description>	So, a good start to the day on Tuesday, when we started our mission over to Barcelona. We caught the easybus from Baker Street in London and it was supposed to take us to London Luton. There was only me, Tink and Mogs on the bus, so we were having ...</description>
		<link>http://www.flashguru.co.uk/barcelona-baby/</link>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>